# Santiago Lopez

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

#### **Details**

Alvarado, Texas lopez.www2012@gmail.com

### Skills

JavaScript

React

Node

React Native

Next.js

Blockchain

Web3.js

Solidity

#### Languages

English

**Angular** 

Vue

#### About me

I'm a senior web/mobile developer with team-leading experience building successful products from ground up.

In the past 8 years, I've worked with both startup and enterprise clients to develop solutions that are reliable, cohesive, and well-accepted by users.

I'm passionate about tech, stocks and finance, cryptocurrencies, and blockchain.

## **Employment History**

### Frontend & Blockchain Developer at Clutch Wallet, Contract, Remote

FEBRUARY 2021 — FEBRUARY 2023

- Worked with React.js, Responsive design, NFTs, and API integration.
- Worked on a mobile wallet development with React Native, Firebase and Expo.
- Worked with UI frameworks like Bootstrap and Tailwind CSS to build responsive pages.
- Used declarative language, Typescript, for better error handling in large applications.
- Development of Smart contracts on Ethereum.
- Worked with smart contract integration using web3.

#### Senior Web Developer at Streebo, Full time, Remote

SEPTEMBER 2018 — JANUARY 2021

- Built complex applications using technologies including React, Redux, Node, Angular and GraphQL, as well as cloud technologies such as Firestore for dashboard and admin panels.
- Worked with the statistical analytics team to ensure quality and performance.
- Provided consulting services for clients and assisted them through project ideation.

### Full Stack Developer at Rocket Insights, Remote

NOVEMBER 2016 — JUNE 2018

- I was involved in building web and mobile applications using React, Next.js, Vue, Vuex, Vuetify, Microservice, WebSocket, TypeScript, Node/Express, and relational databases like PostgreSQL and MySQL.
- On the frontend, I have worked with Redux and Vuex for state management, as well as building responsive and accessible user interfaces. I have also used Next.js to build server-side rendered applications with excellent performance and SEO.
- On the backend, I have worked with Node/Express to build RESTful APIs, implementing features such as authentication, data validation, and error handling.

### Frontend Developer at ActiveProspect, Remote

 ${\tt AUGUST~2014-OCTOBER~2016}$ 

- Built an eCommerce site (PWA) and Mobile app using Ionic, Angular and bigCommerce.

Skills: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, AngularJS, Angular 2, Ionic.

# **Education**

## **Bachelor of Technology, Midwestern State University**

APRIL 2013 — OCTOBER 2014

Computer and Information Science

#### **UEPA**

SEPTEMBER 2010 — MARCH 2013

**Computer Science**